What was that just now?
Kawachi
Yeah? That's fine...
I was just about to get up...
Oh, I see. Got it.
I told you not to worry about it.
We'll negotiate with the other side next week. Okay?
Talk to you later.
My grandfather died last night.
That dream I had...
Was that Grandpa and...
Mom?
Seems he'd lost touch with all of the relatives...
I come back after all this time and it's for a funeral...
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
I'm here.
Oh! Daikichi, you got here fast.
Put your luggage in Grandpa's bedroom, okay?
Yeah.
There was some little girl in the garden.
Was that Haruko's girl? I can't remember.
That wasn't Reina-chan...
Whose kid is she?
Sheesh! This kitchen is difficult to use.
I wonder what I should do from now on.
He was 79 and had a peaceful death, didn't he?
Apparently, that girl is Grandpa's illegitimate child...
Hah?!
Grandpa's child?!
Grandpa didn't say a thing about it...
And his lover took off, too...
His lover?! He was 79!
It's so embarrassing, not to mention shameful...
Then she's...
like your little sister...
and my aunt...
Seriously! How can you joke around about this?!
You're 30 years old! Old enough not to make such thoughtless remarks!
You died at peace, huh, Grandpa?
About how much should I put in?
Note: It's traditional to give money as a condolence gift, known as koden.
As much as you like. It can be any amount.
I know, but there's a certain standard amount, isn't there?
Honestly, any amount is fine...
Although these days, it's very common for sutras to be recited
and a posthumous Buddhist name to be given...
She said 400,000 to 500,000 yen.
That's a large sum of money.
Hello. It's been a long time.
Oh, Daikichi. Long time no see.
Have you been busy?
Yes, busy enough...
You always say you're busy! Too busy to visit your own mother...
He didn't even come home for New Year's.
Stop running! Reina!
Stop it! Reina!
Haruko!
Oh, Dai-chan! Long time no see!
Mama!
Reina!
Gotcha!
Now be a good girl and don't run around!
No way! I don't wanna!
What?
Nothing.
You look a lot like your grandfather did when he was younger.
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, from my mom earlier.
I wonder if it's true.
I'm sure my elder brother was lonely living alone, but...
Apparently, there's a Maternal and Child Health Handbook.
It says her name is "Rin."
Nevertheless, we're talking about a 79-year-old man...
Well, setting aside that it was Father,
somehow I actually feel like he did an admirable job.
Daikichi, would you bring the cushions out of the closet for me?
Sure.
What?
Hey...
Let's swap!
No!
Leave it like it is!
I did it!
Hey, look! Look!
Reina, don't run!
Oh, how clever!
Is it pretty?
It certainly is! You're very good at cat's cradle, Reina-chan!
Next, try to make a four-square ladder!
Mmm...
Oh, my, Reina-chan... Here, let me show you.
Uh-uh!
Poop bomb!
Stop it this instant, Reina!
Uncle, Uncle...
Please, sleep before I do.
I'll take my turn watching the incense.
Oh, I see.
Hey, don't sleep in here!
Let's get some rest over there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi says he'll watch over it.
Oof...
Take care of my big brother.
You get some sleep over there, too.
I'm fine...
What an unsightly face.
All right, everyone.
Please say your final farewells.
Rest in peace.
Big brother...
Grandpa...
I'll see you soon.
Reina! Come along!
Okay!
It's time to say goodbye to Grandpa.
Okay.
A field of flowers!
Stop it!
No! I'm making a field of flowers!
I wanna make it!
You, too, come over here and say goodbye.
Place these on Grandpa.
Hey!
Rindou...
[ Note: Rindou means Bellflower ]
Grandpa loved that flower...
That flower makes Grandpa the happiest.
He's not going to wake up again?
No. He's not going to wake up.
You really are Grandpa's child, aren't you?
Where did this "Yoshii Masako" go?
I don't think any good would come of finding the person
who abandoned her child and ran away.
How utterly irresponsible!
My big brother also was stubborn about it.
Watch it!
That girl can't talk!
It's annoying!
And she still has all of her baby teeth!
She can talk!
And she's not annoying!
She can not talk!
That's why, you know...
Reina, you know...
is bored!
Here! You can have all these if you go away!
You're like a candy shop owner!
Sorry, Dai-chan.
Setting aside the matter of future plans,
who's going to take care of that child right now?
It'd be impossible for us,
since we're running the shop...
If she were a little more proper...
And she seems to be suffering from delayed speech, too...
Mom...
You're at home. Why don't you take her in for a while?
Y-You know that'd be impossible!
I don't have that much free time on my hands!
Do you understand how hard it is to raise a child?!
Haven't I made enough sacrifices over the years?!
If she were taken in half-heartedly, it'd only end up being bad for her.
Wasn't this meeting supposed to be about who would care for Rin?
It's not like you have any intention of doing anything, do you, big brother?
Look at it a bit more realistically.
In the first place, I'm not even certain that she truly is Grandpa's child.
See? You haven't thought it through, so you can't even reply.
For now, I say we try to place her in a facility as quickly as possible...
What?!
Rin!
Wanna come to my place?
Hey! Daikichi!
Brother?!
Old man, I'm hungry...
O-Old man...?!
Don't call me "old man"!
Out of the two of us, you're my aunt!
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Is it good?
Uh-huh.
More?
All we have left is rice.
I'll make a rice ball...
I don't have anything to put in the rice ball.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey! That's still hot!
Look!
But it'll have a tender taste.
Here, old man.
I mean... Daikichi!
Daikichi is strange too...
It's good.
Nice to meet you, my name is Kaga Rin.
Today I'm going to a new nursery school.
But everybody already went home.
Isn't he going to pick me up soon?
Daikichi...
Chikyuu...
Earth...
Uchuu...
Space...
U... U...
Usukuchi Shouyu.
Light flavored Soy Sauce.
Yu... Yu...
Yubikiri genman
The next story is "Pinky Swear."
Episode 2
Pinky Swear
Oh no, it ended in an "n"!